Welcome to computer vision.
コンピュータービジョンにようこそ
Robotics can essentially be broken down into a three step cycle.
ロボットは基本的に 3 ステップのサイクルに分けることができます
The first step is to sense or perceive the world,
第 1 のステップで周りの世界を感知したり知覚します
the second step is to decide what to do based on that perception,
第 2 のステップでその認知に基づいて対応を決定します
and the third step is to perform an action to carry out that decision.
第 3 のステップでその決定を遂行するためにアクションを実行します
Computer vision is a major part of the perception step in that cycle.
コンピュータービジョンは このサイクルでの認知ステップの主要部分です
If you ask Sebastian,
Sebastian に尋ねれば
he will tell you that 80% of the challenge of building a self-driving car is perception.
彼は自動運転車を作るという課題の 80% は認知だと答えるでしょう
This module is all about perception.
このモジュールでは認知のすべてを扱います
Computer vision is the art and science of
コンピュータービジョンとは 技術であり
perceiving and understanding the world around you through images.
周りの世界を画像から知覚して理解する術にあたります
In the case of self-driving cars,
自動運転車の場合
computer vision helps us detect lane markings,
コンピュータービジョンが車線標示
vehicles, pedestrians, and other elements in the environment in order to navigate safely.
車両 歩行者などの要素を環境から検出して安全な走行を実現します
Later in this nano degree program,
後ほどこの Nanodegree プログラムで
we will be using laser and radar data for the task of perception.
レーザーとレーダーのデータを認知のタスクに使用します
So, you might ask, "Why bother doing this at all with
そこでこう尋ねるかもしれません  なぜこんな面倒なことを
camera images when we have more sophisticated instruments at our disposal? "
カメラ画像でやるのか  もっと高度な機器が自由に使えるときに
So, why are we doing this David?
なぜこんなことをしているんですか David
Good question. Self-driven cars employ a suite of sophisticated sensors,
良い質問ですね  自動運転車は高度なセンサー一式を利用していますが
but humans do the job of driving with just two eyes and one good brain.
人間は運転という仕事を 2 つの目と優秀な頭脳 1 つだけでこなします
In fact, we can even do it with one eye closed.
実際は片方の目をつぶっていても運転できますね
Indeed, we can. So, let's take a closer look at why using
確かにできますね  では理由を詳しく見ていきましょう
cameras instead of other sensors might be an advantage in developing self-driving cars.
なぜ他のセンサーでなくカメラを使用すると自動運転車を作る際に利点があるのか説明します
Radar and Lidar see the world in 3D,
レーダーとライダーは実世界を 3D で見ます
which can be a big advantage for knowing where you are relative to your environment.
このことは 周りの環境に対する自分の位置を把握するのに大きな利点となります
A camera sees in 2D,
カメラは 2D で見ますが
but at much higher spatial resolution than Radar and Lidar such that
空間分解能はレーダーとライダーよりはるかに高機能で
it's actually possible to infer depth information from camera images.
実際にカメラ画像から詳細な情報を推測できます
The big difference, however,
ただし 大きな違いは
comes down to cost, where cameras are significantly cheaper.
コストということになります  カメラのほうがかなり安価です
That's right. It is altogether possible that self-driving cars will eventually be
そのとおりです  自動運転車はそのうち
outfitted with just a handful of cameras and a really smart algorithm to do the driving.
わずかなカメラと実に高性能なアルゴリズムだけを搭載して走行できるようになるでしょう
That's why we're really excited to dive into computer vision with you in this module.
そういうわけで コンピュータービジョンをこのモジュールで学ぶのがとても楽しみです